[MUSIC]
[음악]
Okay.
좋아요.
Well instead of the analysis that we just did,
방금 한 분석 대신에
we can instead think about modeling the relationship
주택의 평수와 판매 가격 간의 관련성
between the square footage of the house and the house sales price.
모델링에 대해 생각해보죠
And to do this, we're gonna use something that's called linear regression.
그러기 위해서 선형회귀법이란 걸 사용합니다
Okay, so to leverage all the observations that we've collected, what we wanna do is
지금까지 수집한 모든 관찰 결과를 반영하기 위해서는
be able to understand the relationship between the square foot of the house and
주택의 평수와 판매 가격 사이의 관련성을
the house sales price.
찾아내야 합니다
And so the simplest model we can use for this,
가장 간단한 모델은
is just fitting a line through the data.
데이터를 따라 회귀직선을 그리는 것이지요
So here's an example of a line fit to this data.
이 데이터에 맞는 회귀직선의 예입니다
And this line is defined by an intercept W0 and a slope W1.
절편 w0와 기울기 w1로 정의되어 있죠
And so often we'll talk about W1 being the weight on the feature X or
w1은 흔히 특징 x의 가중치 또는
its called the regression coefficient.
회귀계수라고 불립니다
And what this weight has an interpretation of,
이 가중치를 해석하면 이렇습니다
is as we vary X, the square footage of the house,
주택 평수 x가 변화할 때
how much of an impact does that have on changes in the observed house sales price?
관찰 중인 주택 판매 가격에 얼마나 영향을 끼치는가?
Okay, so these two things, our intercept and
이 절편과 기울기가
our slope are the parameters of our model.
우리 모델의 파라미터입니다
And so, to be very explicit here, we're gonna write this function,
확실하게 하기 위해 여기 이 함수,
this linear function here, with the subscript W,
선형 함수의 아래 첨자 w는 함수가
that indicates that this function is specified by parameters.
파라미터에 의해 결정되었음을 나타냅니다
W being the set of W0 and W1.
w는 w0와 w1의 집합이죠
Okay, so this is the line that we fit through the data.
데이터에 맞춰 그린 회귀직선입니다
But a question is, which line is the right line or a good line to use for
하지만 어떤 선이 주어진 데이터 세트에
a given data set.
사용하기 맞고 좋을까요?
So maybe we could draw this line or this one instead.
어쩌면 이거나 이게 더 나을지도 모르죠
And each one of those is given by a different set of parameters w.
파라미터 w 집합의 값을 다르게 함으로써 그릴 수 있습니다
And a question is which w do we want to choose for our model?
그러니까 모델을 세우기 위해 어떤 w를 고르란 말이죠?
Okay, well, to think about this, let's talk about defining a cost for
주어진 선에 대해
a given line.
비용을 정의해 봅시다
And one very common cost associated with a specific fit to
데이터에 맞춘 특정 회귀직선과 관련해
the data is something called the residual sum of squares.
흔히 쓰이는 비용은 잔차제곱합이라고 합니다
So, the residual sum of squares, we take our fitted line and
잔차제곱합에서는 회귀직선과
we look at each of our observations.
각 관찰 결과를 봅니다
And we look at how far is that observation
그리고 모델의 예측과 관찰 결과가
from what the model would predict.
얼마나 떨어져 있는지 보죠
Which is just the point on the line.
결과라도 해도 그냥 선에 있는 점이지만요
So we look at all of these distances here, and
이 거리를 살펴보고
we actually look at the square of these distances.
사실은 거리의 제곱을 보죠
That's why it's called the residual.
잔차라 불리는 이유입니다
The residual is the difference of your prediction and your actual observation.
잔차는 예측값과 실제 관찰 결과 간의 차이입니다
We're gonna look at the square and we're going to sum over them.
제곱의 합을 구합니다
Okay, so this is the equation, here more explicitly, where we have the price,
이게 공식인데 가격이 있죠
this is our observed house sales price for the first house.
첫 번째 주택의 판매 가격입니다
And what is this term here?
이 항은 뭐냐고요?
So, if this is what I'm calling dollar house one,
이게 달러 주택 일호라고 하면
then what this point here is,
여기 이 점은
is if this is square footage of house one.
주택 일호의 평수인 거죠
Then this x that I've drawn here
여기 제가 그린 x는
represents exactly this term here.
정확히 이 항을 말합니다
This is that value, the point on the line.
이게 선 위의 점인 것이죠
So this dollar sign minus this term here is
그러니 달러 기호 빼기 이 항은
the difference between our observed house price versus what our model,
관찰된 주택 가격과 이 선으로 표현되는
just this line, predicts for this given house square foot.
예측값의 차이가 되는 것이죠
And we're squaring that and
그걸 제곱해서
we're summing over all the different houses in our data set.
데이터 세트에 있는 모든 주택에 대한 합계를 구합니다
Okay, so we think about trying to find the best line according to this metric that
여기서 정의한 척도와 잔차제곱합를 기준으로
I've defined here, this residual sum of squares,
회귀직선을 찾아보도록 하죠
what we do is we research over all possible W 0 and W 1.
w0과 w1 사이의 가능한 모든 수를 대입해봅니다
So all possible lines,
가능한 모든 선을 살펴보고
and we choose the one that minimizes the residual sum of squares.
그중 잔차제곱합을 최소화하는 값을 찾습니다
So we're gonna denote the resulting W as W hat.
찾아낸 w를 w 모자로 표시합니다
So remember that's gonna be the set of w hat zero, and w hat one.
이렇게 해서 w 모자 0, w 모자 1의 집합이 되죠
Our intercept and our slope.
절편과 기울기입니다
Okay.
좋아요.
So there exists really nice and efficient algorithms for
w 모자 계산에 꽤 괜찮고 빠른 알고리즘이 존재하는데
computing this w hat, this search over all possible ws.
이 모델의 파라미터인
We could look at parameters of this model.
w에 가능한 값을 모두 대입해보죠
But we're gonna discuss these algorithms more in the regression course.
회귀 강의에서 이 알고리즘에 대해 더 자세히 공부할 겁니다
Ok, so now let's talk about how to take our estimated model parameters and
이제 예측 모델 파라미터를 가지고
use them to predict the value of my house.
저희 집의 가치를 예측하는 방법을 알아봅시다
So I've gone through, sorry, this star shouldn't be there.
죄송합니다 여긴 별이 아니라
This should be a hat, just to be clear.
모자가 들어가야 하죠
And I've gone through and plotted the line
예측된 w0 모자와 w1 모자에
associated with our estimated w0 hat and w1 hat.
대응하는 선을 그렸습니다
And now, here's my house.
이제 여기 저희 집이 있습니다
This is its square footage.
이건 집의 평수고요
And the best guess of my house price, is simply what the line predicts.
주택 가격에 대한 최선의 추측은 단순하게 선의 예측과 같습니다
So I go, and I compute what is the value for this square footage of my house.
저희 집 평수를 대입해서 수치를 계산해 보도록 하죠
Which is W0 hat plus W1 hat times the square footage
w0 모자 더하기 w1 모자 곱하기
of my house okay very, very straightforward.
집의 평수니 아주 쉽죠
[MUSIC]
[음악]